[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Windows 7 is an ……………… System.",
    "ans": [
      "DOS",
      "Application",
      "Operating",
      "All of These"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "विंडोज 7 एक ……………… सिस्टम है।",
    "ansHindi": [
      "",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correctAns": "Operating",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Mouse, Keyboard and Joystick are examples of ………………?",
    "ans": [
      "Output Device",
      "Processing Device",
      "Input Device",
      "None of These"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "माउस, कीबोर्ड और जॉयस्टिक ……………… के उदाहरण हैं?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "आउटपुट डिवाइस",
      "प्रसंस्करण उपकरण",
      "इनपुट डिवाइस",
      "इनमें से कोई नहीं"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Input Device",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Who is known as the Mother of Computer?",
    "ans": [
      "Madam Currie",
      "Lise Neitner",
      "Lady Ada Augusta",
      "Asina Chatterjee"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "कंप्यूटर की जननी के रूप में किसे जाना जाता है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correctAns": "Lady Ada Augusta",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Which memory is known as Volatile type of Memory?",
    "ans": [
      "ROM",
      "EPRAM",
      "RAM",
      "PROM"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "किस मेमोरी को वोलेटाइल प्रकार की मेमोरी के रूप में जाना जाता है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correctAns": "RAM",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "How many Types of Software are there?",
    "ans": [
      "Two",
      "Three",
      "Four",
      "Five"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "सॉफ्टवेयर कितने प्रकार के होते हैं?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "दो",
      "तीन",
      "चार",
      "पाँच"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Two",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Which of the following is an Output Device?",
    "ans": [
      "Scanner",
      "Mouse",
      "Monitor",
      "Joystick"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "निम्न में से कौन एक आउटपुट डिवाइस है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "स्कैनर",
      "माउस",
      "मॉनीटर",
      "जॉयस्टिक"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Monitor",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Difference Engine was developed by?",
    "ans": [
      "IBM",
      "Charles Babbage",
      "John Napier",
      "Chinese"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "डिफरेंस इंजन किसके द्वारा विकसित किया गया था?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correctAns": "Charles Babbage",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "The Motherboard is attached ……………… the Computer.",
    "ans": [
      "Inside",
      "Outside",
      "At the Top of",
      "At the Bottom of"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "मदरबोर्ड ……………… कंप्यूटर से जुड़ा है।",
    "ansHindi": [
      "",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correctAns": "Inside",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Computer has ……………… IQ.",
    "ans": [
      "Full",
      "50%",
      "No",
      "None of These"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "कंप्यूटर में ……………… आईक्यू है।",
    "ansHindi": [
      "पूरा",
      "50%",
      "नहीं",
      "इनमें से कोई नहीं"
    ],
    "correctAns": "No",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "subject": "Computer",
    "round": "round4",
    "question": "Which of the following is a Storage Device?",
    "ans": [
      "DVD",
      "Speaker",
      "CPU",
      "Keyboard"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "निम्न में से कौन एक स्टोरेज डिवाइस है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ],
    "correctAns": "DVD",
    "enable": true
  }
]